Guide to the Max Shachtman Papers TAM.103
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I: Groups with which Shachtman was affiliated (microfilmed)
  - PART D: THE INTERNATIONAL LEFT OPPOSITION AND FOURTH INTERNATIONAL
    - Summary, minutes, motions of Second World Congress of F.I. (French, English) Fourth International, Apr 1948 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Report on the F.I. Since the Outbreak of the War (English), 1939-1948 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Plenum of the International Executive Comittee of F.I. (preparing Second World Congress, in English and French), Sep 1947 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Motions and Resolutions of the 5th Plenum of I.E.C. or F.I., Feb 1948 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - World Situation and the tasks of the F.I. (draft resolution), Nov 1947 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - The F.I. and Stalinism (draft theses), Nov 1947 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Statement by International Secretariat of F.I. on Korea (French), Jul 1950 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Open letter from I.S. of F.I. to Yugoslav C.P. (in French), 1948 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Circular of I.S. of F.I. about Tito, Jun 1948 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - I.P.S. Newsletter (#4) from the I.S., Jul 1948 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Left Opposition - loose typescripts (in French, English) Sections of the Left Opposition, 1930s (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Position paper Re: the Workers Party of the U.S. and the 4th International, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - (no folder), undated (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - All American Pacific Bureau International Conference (steno notes), Mar 20, 1938-Mar 23, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - All American Pacific Bureau Minutes, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - All American Pacific Bureau Theses and Resolutions, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 41)
      Microfilm Reel Number 7
    - Reports on conditions in various Latin American countries and the situation in sections of the F.I., late1940s (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Austria, International Left Opposition - misc. internal material, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Belgium, (Jeunesse Revolutionaire) Youth Section of Belgium F.I., 1930s (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Belgium, L.C.I. Federation de Bruxelles documents sur la Crise Interieure de la section Belge (sormmire mars 1938; bulletin), 1934 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Belgium, Parti Socialiste Revolutionaire Belgium, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Belgium, L'Union des Communistes Internationals, early1930s (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Brazil, L.C.I. Brazilian Section, 1936, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Britain, Militant group, British faction of F.I., mid1930s (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Britain, R.E.P. - British F.I. (bulletins), 1938 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Britain, Marxist group, British faction of F.I. (bulletin, handwritten letter), mid1930s (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Britain, Revolutionary Socialist League, British faction of F. I. (letter), 1938 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      Microfilm Reel Number 8
    - Britain, Unity and Peace Agreement of RSL and RSP and Militant Group, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Canada, Workers Party of Canada, Canadian F.I. (minority document), late1930s-1940s (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Chile, Izquierda Communista, Santiago Chile (L.C.I.), 1936 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - China, Communist League of China, Nov 12, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Cuba, Izquierda Communista Cuba (leaflet), 1933 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Cuba, Revolutionary Workers Party Cuban Section of F.I. (in Spanish, English translation), undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - France, Communist League of France (in English, leaflet in French), ca.1934 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - France, Comite des Jeunes Pour La 4e Internationale (leaflet), Sep 1939 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - France, Parti Ouvier Internationaliste (French section of F.I.; leaflets) (see also: correspondence 1936,1937), 1934-1938 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - France, Declaration of Jewish group in Paris (in English, French), ca.1934 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - France, P.C.I. France (Bureau Politique Report), Jun 1947 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - France, Le Redressement Communiste, organe de l'opposition francais, 1927-1929 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - France, Resolution Sur les Exclusions dans la section francais, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - France, Pourquoi nous avons adhere a la Quatri'eme Internationale (why we affiliated with the F.I., P.C.I.), undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - France, La Nuova impresa africana de capitalismo italiano (in Italian, pub. in France by Gruppo), undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - France, Aux membres du PSOP (in French), late1930s (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Germany, AK of IKD (Wochenbriefe #1-3, handwritten "The Situation in German Section" Nov.1934), 1934-1944 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Germany, International Left Opposition, undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Germany, International Left Opposition, 1929-1934 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Greece, Archio Marxistas and L'opposition de gauche du PCG (two factions, I.S. letters to PCG), 1934 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Holland, RSAP (Resolution concerning the relations between RSAP and I.S. of F.I.), 1938 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - India, B.L.P.I. (Indian Section) Amendment to the Russian Theses (passed unanimously by the CC of BLPI), Mar 18, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Italy, Partit Operaio Communista (Bolscevico-Leninista) Italian F.I. (bulletin n.d., leaflet), 1945-1947 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Italy, Partito Communista Internazionalista (F.I.) Italian, ca.1940s (Box 5, Folder 29)
      Microfilm Reel Number 9
    - Mexico, L.C.I./Bolshevik-Leninist de Mejico (from SI, FI in French), Nov 26, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Mexico, Discussion material of Mexican Section (in Spanish), 1947 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Peru, Re: Formation of a section of F.I. in Peru (in Spanish), Jan 1938 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Russia, Le Situation des Bolsheviks - Leninistes Russes (in Russian), undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - South Africa, Revolutionary Workers Party (Lenin Club), undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Spain, Izquierda Communista Espan"ola (letter from P. Frank and M.S., June 1933; see also: M.S. manuscripts in Series IV) (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Spain, Grupo Communista Internacionalista (Spanish section' F.I.; bulletin) L.O. and F.I. Individuals, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Adolphe (letter to I.S. March 13, 1937, in French) (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Andre (report from France, March 25, 1936?), ca.1936 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Ciart (member of I.B. for the F.I.; letter dated March 24, 1937) (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Frank, Pierre and M.S. (to C.C. of.Comunist League Feb.26,1934; see also: R. Molinier 5/53) (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - G'l'tlow, Ben (bloc against Stalin), ca.1933 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Grandizo, Manuel Fernandez (Munis, G.) (Reponse au Comrade Munis; also in English, June 1947; see also: Series I, Parts G & H) (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Guerin, R. (La Question Russe Doit Etre Revise, April 16, 1946) (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Hennaut, A. (Directives pour une Action, Dec. 1931) (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Lambert, Pierre (Coment rem~dier a la diminution de pouvoir d1achat des masses laboreuses, Oct. 21, 1946) (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Landau, Kurt, early1930s (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Lhuilier, J. (Document on the question of French Ligue, July 16, 1934 2 different documents') (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Lucien (Assez de Talmudisme, Ayons Enfin un Politique, April 15/May 3, 1946) (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Ludwig (letter March 28, 1940, WP opposition to SWP before split' 1940; see also: folder,50) (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - MacDonald, DwijR-t/=He Correspondence (Resolution uber Stalins; Einfall in Finnland Held' Dec.27, 1939, correspondence Feb.7, 1940, in German; see also: 3/8), 1939-1940 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Magnin, Louis (Lettre aux-Tr-o-tsl7ists sur le RDR - attached note), Apr 19, 1948-Apr 22, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Manos (Greek section) (Letter to Swabeck), Nov 1940 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Molinier, R./Frank P. (Que Fera La Paix Durable) see also; 5/40, Oct 1939 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Plaville (letter to Van, Feb.25,1937; apres la ConT. Nationale de la Ligue Communiste, Oct.6,1931), 1931, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - (Rizzi) Bruno (Le Collectivisme Bureaucratique Preface, July 15, 1939) (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Sedova-Trotsky,Natalia, G. Munis and Benjamin Peret (La IV Internationale En Danger - June 27, 1947; Carta Abierta Al Partido Communista - June 1947) (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Sneevliet, H. (see also: correspondence I.S. 1936 Box 4) (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Spector, Maurice (to Canadian Immigration, Nov.l5,1933) (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Swabeck, Arne (correspondence with Clart, Braun, Adolph) (see also: folders on CLA/WPUS, SWP), 1937 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - PART E: AMERICAN LEFT-WING OPPOSITION: COMMUNIST LEAGUE OFAMERICA
    For additional material, see also Series VI. Addendum (not filmed), Box 52, folder 1-3: Communist League of America Minutes, 1929-1933.
    - Workers (Communist) Party of America Left Opposition (leaflet, A Challenge to Debate), ca.1929 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Communist League of America Correspondence with Int'l (see also: Box 4 I.C.L. Correspondence of I.S. and I.B.), 1931 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence with Int'l (see also: Box 4 I.C.L. Correspondence of I.S. and I.B.T, 1934-1935 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence with Int'l (see also: Box 4 I.C.L. Correspondence of Movement for the F.I.), 1936-1937 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Letter from International Bulletin of L.O. (in French from Paris), ca.1930 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - National Committee Minutes (except 1930), 1929-1934 (Box 6, Folder 6-10)
    - National Committee Resolution, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - National Office (N.O.) Communication to N.C. Members, 1933-1934 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - N.O. Communication to branches, 1931-1934 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - M.S. notes, 1931-1932 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - M.S. Resolutions and Statements, 1932-1933 (Box 6, Folder 15-16)
    - Statements and Resolutions (folder 19 contains N.C. Resolution on composition of NY local; folder 20 contains merger proposals to AWP and CIA), 1931-1934 (Box 6, Folder 17-20)
    - M.S. Correspondence with I.S., 1931-1932 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - M.S. Correspondence with other CIA members, 1929-1933 (Box 6, Folder 22-26)
    - M.S. Correspondence with CLA members (folder 28: Joe Hansen), 1933-1934 (Box 6, Folder 27-28)
    - 3 telegrams to M.S. from Arverne, 1931 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - B.J. Field (N.C. statements on expulsion proposal statement to NY local), 1933-1934 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Two letters from Albert Glotzer (in Paris) to N.E.C., 1931 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence between other CIA members (not M.S.), 1930-1934 (Box 6, Folder 32-34)
    - Outline of speech by Cannon to NY Branch (The Policy of the opposition of the Present Tasks), Dec 23, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - NY Branch Report on Internal Situation by A. Glotzer, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Resolution of the E.C. of NY Branch, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Report on Unser Kampf (Yiddish L.O. publ.), 1932 (Box 6, Folder 37A)
    - American Workers Party (Pittsburgh Convention, Dec.2-3, 1933; Report on POC meeting of AWP, Nov.6,1935), 1933-1935 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - PART F: WORKERS PARTY U.S. (TROTSKYIST) AND ENTRY INTO SOCIALIST PARTY
    - National Committee Resident on the International Plenum (report by M.S. 7/12/25), 1935 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Report on the International Conference for the F I - by M.S., Nov.5,1936 (see also 4/37), undated (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - N.C. Correspondence with RSWP Holland, Jul 18, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 40A)
    - Minutes of N.C. (see also: Box 4), Dec 3, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 40B)
    - Pittsburgh (MarchT-PTe-num Minutes and Statements, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - June Plenum Minutes and Statements, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - October Plenum Minutes and Statements, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Statement of N.C. of WPUS and SYL (Spartacist Youth League) (Re: Entry into SP and disolution of WP and SYL), 1936 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Political Committee (P.C.) Minutes, Dec 1934 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - P.C. Minutes, 1935-1936 (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
      Microfilm Reel Number 12
    - P.C. Memorandum (fusion CIA and AWP), Aug 12, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Secretariat Minutes, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - National Secretary's Report, Dec 3, 1934-Jan 10, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - N.O. Correspondence with N.C. Members, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - N.O. Correspondence with N.C. Members, Dec 1934-Jun 1935 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - N.O. Correspondnece with branches (folder 9: Harsh incident in Philadelphia), 1935-1936 (Box 7, Folder 9-10)
    - Letters, statements, resolution of Majority factions (Cannon, Shachtman, Weber, etc.), 1934-1936 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Letters, statements, resolutions - Muste, Weber Minority Faction, 1934-1936 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Letters, statements, resolutions - Oehler, Stamm, Basky Minority Faction, 1934-1936 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Letters, statements, resolutions, 1935-1936 (Box 7, Folder 14-16)
      Microfilm Reel Number 12 (Reel 13 begins with folder 15)
    - M.S. correspondence with other WPUS Members, 1935-1936 (Box 7, Folder 17-18)
      Microfilm Reel Number 13 (begins with folder 15, above)
    - M.S. notes on internal discussion (report to the district conventions, NY; handwritten), Aug 10, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 19)
      Microfilm Reel Number 13
    - Muste letter to editor of Arbeiderbladet, Oslo, Norway Martin Tranmael, editor), Jul 5, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - New York District, 1934-1936 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Spartacist Youth League (SYL), 1935 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - SYL Marxist Action Group (Minority Faction), 1936 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Leaflets'(folder 24: new international; folder 26: clippings), 1930s (Box 7, Folder 24-26)
    - Spartacus Youth Club Toronto (F.I.) (expulsion of T.P. Mill, A. Jail, and S. Campbell), 1934 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Revolutionary Workers League (Oehler Group), 1936 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - League for a Revolutionary Workers Party (B.F. Field Group), 1936 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Socialist Party - Trotskyists on SP (organizing comittee for the SP Convention - OCSP), 1936-1937 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - PART G: SOCIALIST WORKERS PARTY
    - Founding Convention documents and minutes, (ISP, International Socialist Party, one of the names considered and used at the convention), Dec 31, 1937-Jan 3, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      Microfilm Reel Number 14
    - Convention (Agenda, M.S. handwritten notes organizational report), 1939 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Convention Call, minutes, notes, Apr 5, 1940-Apr 8, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 2A)
    - Plenum, Chicago (minutes), Jan 3, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Plenum, N.Y.C. (folder 4 contains minutes and materials submitted; folder 5 contains agenda, minutes), 1938 (Box 8, Folder 4-5)
    - Plenum (minutes, resolutions on youth, resolutions on Maritime), Jul 6, 1939-Jul 7, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Political Committee (folder 11 contains use of pseudonyms), 1938-1940 (Box 8, Folder 7-11)
      Microfilm Reel Number 14 (Reel 15 begins with folder 8)
    - National Office Correspondence with N.C. Members (folder 12 contains circular #2 June 11, 1938; very confidential); (folder 13 contains circular #3 May 13, 1939; confidential, letter from Raus(France) Internal Bulletin of N.C.), 1938-1940 (Box 8, Folder 12-13)
      Microfilm Reel Number 15 (begins with folder 8, above)
    - National Office Correspondence with Branches and Locals (folder 14 contains Bulletin #1 Feb. 11, 1938, circular letter #6 Feb. 14, 1938, circular letter #7 March 2, 1938, circular letter #9 March is, 1938), 1938-1940 (Box 8, Folder 14-15)
      Microfilm Reel Number 15
    - P.C. Resolutions on application of "The Death Agony of Capitalism and Tasks of F.I." (proposed amendment), 1938 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - P.C. Statement on Invasion of Finland, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - P.C. Discussion with Maritime Fraction, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 18)
      Microfilm Reel Number 16
    - P.C. Speech by Martin Abern (Reply to Burnham documents), Jun 1939 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Draft Thesis on the Minnesota Farmer Labor Party, ca.1938 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Internal Discussion majority documents (Cannon), 1939-1940 (Box 8, Folder 21-22)
    - Internal Discussion minority documents (Shachtman) (Motions in Branch minutes), 1939-1940 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Lyons, Eugene (letter to editors of New International), undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Internal Discussion minority documents (Shachtman) (see also: Box 2/48 and 48A), 1939-1944 (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
    - Statements, Resolutions, Reports (except 1941-42), 1938-1940 (Box 9, Folder 3-4)
    - M.S. Correspondence with other SWP Members (see also: 5-6 [one folder]' M.S. Correspondence 5/30), 1938-1940 (Box 9, Folder 5-6)
    - M.S. Notes, ca.1938 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - J.P. Cannon Correspondence (in SP 1936-37, see also: M.S. Correspondence 5/28), 1936-1940 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      Microfilm Reel Number 17
    - James Burnham article and letter ("Science and Style, The Politics of Desperation!'), ca.1940 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence between other SWP Members (Not M.S.), 1939-1940 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence with other Political Groups, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence from Secretary of President of Mexico (to Cannon and Shachtman, in Spanish), Mar 24, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Anti-War Fund Campaign (Bulletin #1 12/15/39, Bulletin #2 12/2S/39, Bulletin #4 3/11/38, Circular #2 12/12/39), 1938 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - NY Local Material on 14th Congress District Election, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - NY Local Party Action (Organizational and informational Bulletins #6,7,8,12), 1940 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Material after 1940 Split (letter from Berta Langston, leaflet-L.A. Campaign), 1940-1970 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - NY Local - leaflet (Workers of NY!! Who Will Smash Loughlin?), 1939 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - St. Paul, Minnesota and Minneapolis ("Jules Geller for Mayor," "Vote the Union Ticket"), ca.1938 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - YPSL National Plenum Philadelphia (Report to P.C. Oct.17,1939, M.T. Weiss exchange with Abern), Oct 14, 1939-Oct 15, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - YPSL National Bureau Minutes, Oct 30, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - YPSL (Pre-convention discussion Oct.1938) (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Johnson Forest Tendency (Resignation from SWP; see also: Johnson-Forest Tendency, Box 11/19; 11/20), 1951 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Youth Socialist Alliance, ca.1959 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Minority Conference (in Cleveland, 2 telegrams), Feb 24, 1940-Feb 25, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Minority Convention (Convention minutes, Plenum minutes, results), Apr 5, 1940-Apr 7, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - PART H: WORKERS PARTY (1940-48)
    - Correspondence with F.I. (cover letter by M.S.), 1940 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Plenum Minutes, Feb 5, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - P.C. (Club) Minutes, Apr 1940-Dec 1940 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - P.C. Minutes, ca.1946-1947 (Box 9, Folder 29-30)
    - James Burnham letter of resignation, May 21, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - N.C. Report to N.Y.C. Convention (in note form by M.S.), Nov 1940-Dec 1940 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - N.O. Communication to N.C. Members, ca.1940-1944 (Box 9, Folder 33)
      Microfilm Reel Number 18
    - N.O. Communication to all Branches, 1940-1942 (Box 9, Folder 34-35)
    - N.O. Communication to all Branches and Party Members, 1946-1947 (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Reports,Resolutions, and Statements, 1942-1947 (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
    - Resolution on Russian Question by J.R. Johnson (C.L.R. James) (submitted to 2nd nat'l convention), Sep 19, 1941 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Education Dept. (Nat'l Education Bulletin #1, Political History of W.P., Reference guide to basic documents and supplementary material), 1940 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - N.Y. Local City Convention (report on work from Jan.-Dec.1946), Feb 2, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - N.Y. Branch Material (city letter; April 1940-Dec. 1940, convention call; Apr. 22, 1940; N.Y. City Program of Action May 1 - Sept.15,1940), Apr 1940-Dec 1940 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Undated documents, 1940s (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Socialist Youth League, Correspondence (2 telegrams), 1947 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence with James T. Farrell (Re: copyright of J.T.F. article), 1947-1948 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - M.S. Notes on National Question (answer to J.R. Johnson, C.L.R. James), 1943 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      Microfilm Reel Number 19
    - Resolutions and Proposals on the National Question, 1943-1944 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Discussion on the Labor Party Question (The "Realism" of the Labor Party, The Problem of the Labor Party), 1943-1944 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Discussion on Ernie Erbers' Blue Cover Outline #2 (The Role of the Trade Unions), 1945-1946 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Negroes in the Primaries (Supreme Court Decision on Texas Primaries), 1944 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Historical Development of the Negroes in American Society by J.R. Johnson (C.L.R. James) - Note: p. 1 filmed twice; p. 2 not filmed., Dec 20, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - M.S. Correspondence with United Mine Workers, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - M.S. Correspondence (see also: folders 13-20), 1946-1948 (Box 11, Folder 2-4)
    - Correspondence with Indian S.P., 1950-1951 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence with Ernie Erber (Lundi) with P.C. Members, 1943-1946 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      Microfilm Reel Number 20
    - Correspondence not M.S. (see also: Box 15 Glotzer Correspondence from P.C. 1948-51) (folder 9-correspondence to Stanley (Plastrick) from Ben Goldberg) Paris 3/10/48), 1943, 1947-1948 (Box 11, Folder 7-9)
    - Information Bulletin #1, Excess Profits Tax Bill, 1942 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Social Composition of Party (charts, tasks of the party), Nov 23, 1946-Oct 1, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - M.S. Notes (talks to membership meeting on USSR), ca.1942 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - WP/SWP unity notes by M.S., 1946 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - WP/SWP unity-documents by Felix Morrow (while in SWP), 1946 (Box 11, Folder 13A)
    - WP/SWP unity Jeffries, Lyons' resignation from SWP, 1946 (Box 11, Folder 13B)
    - WP/SWP unity, correspondence and discussion with F.I., 1946-1947 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - WP/SWP unity correspondence, 1945 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - WP/SIAIP unity discussion and correspondence (folder 18 bound contains correspondence in addition to unity), undated, 1945-1947 (Box 11, Folder 16-18)
      Microfilm Reel Number 20 (Reel 21 begins with folder 17)
    - Johnson-Forest Tendencey (Johnson, C.L.R. James, Forest, Raya Dunayevskaya), 1944-1947 (Box 11, Folder 19-20)
      Microfilm Reel Number 21 (begins with folder 17, above)
    - Leaflets, 1940-1947 (Box 11, Folder 21-22)
      Microfilm Reel Number 21
    - W.P. Fourth National Convention of Workers Party (constitution, minutes, agenda), May 27, 1946-May 31, 1946 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Plenum, May 25, 1946 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      Microfilm Reel Number 22
    - Minutes and Circulars, Jan 1946-Mar 1946 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - P.C. Minutes (correspondence and resolutions), Jan 1947-Nov 1947 (Box 12, Folder 4-8)
      Microfilm Reel Number 22 (Reel 23 begins with folder 6, and ends with folder 8)
    - P.C. Minutes (correspondence), Nov 1947-Dec 1947 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      Microfilm Reel Number 24
    - Active Workers Conference (minutes, reports, finances), Oct 1947-Nov 1947 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - P.C. Minutes (folder 3 contains correspondence, folders 4 and 5 contain resolutions), Dec 1947-Dec 1948 (Box 13, Folder 3-5)
      Microfilm Reel Number 24 (Reel 25 begins with folder 5)
    - Fifth National Convention (minutes, resolutions), Mar 24, 1949-Mar 27, 1949 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      Microfilm Reel Number 25 (begins with folder 5, above)
    - Plenum (minutes), Mar 22, 1949-Mar 23, 1949 (Box 14, Folder 2)
      Microfilm Reel Number 25